.
Die Bergkatze was restored in 2000
by the Friedrich Wilhelm Murnau Foundation.
The basis was a camera negative
from the Bundesarchiv-Filmarchiv, Berlin.
The intertitles contained in the negative
do not correspond to
the wording of the censor-card,
and they were in bad condition.
The wording of the reconstructed intertitles
is based on the censor-card.
The copying was carried out
by L'lmmagine Ritrovata in Bologna.
The master negative of this reconstruction
was used in 2014 for the 2K digital version.
THE MOUNTAIN-LION/ THE WILDCAT
A Grotesque in 4 Acts
by Hanns Kräly and Ernst Lubitsch
Direction: Ernst Lubitsch
Sets and Costumes: Ernst Stern
Cinematography: Theodor Sparkuhl
CAST:
The Fortress Commander: Viktor Janson
His Wife: Marga Köhler
Their Daughter: Edith Meller
Lieutenant Alexis: Paul Heidemann
Claudius, Leader of a Band of Robbers:
Wilhelm Diegelmann
Rischka, His Daughter: Pola Negri
Pepo, a Shy Robber: Hermann Thimig
Dafko: Paul Biensfeld
Zofano: Paul Grätz
Masilio: Max Kronert
Tripo: Erwin Kopp
Setting for the action:
not far from Piffkaneiro
FIRST ACT.
Quiet!
Lilli, daughter of the commander.
To the Commander
of the Border Fortress!
Lieutenant ALEXIS has been sent
to your unit as punishment. By decree.
Lieutenant Alexis, who is known
by all the women here as "Dashing Alex",
is to be treated firmly.
- General of Not-Far-from-Piffkaneiro
At last, a dashing man.
What a swine!
That's how you talk about Alexis?
Alexis leaves the residence.
Sweetheart!
A word of send-off. -
The heart breaks, tears well up.
Yearning stings, tonsils swell up...
So take your leave in peace.
You have been good to all of us.
I did what I could.
Adieu! Daddy!
Robber-leader Claudius and his men,
the terror of the border.
Good morning, men!
Good morning, leader sir.
Unload!
Well, what have you stolen?
Where have you been all this time?
I was in Kientopp.
Not on the back of the head
Rischka, my child.
She hit me.
Me too.
Don't spoil them
Towel.
Ah, look here.
Drop your trousers.
As you do to me, so I do to you.
END OF THE FIRST ACT.
SECOND ACT.
The robbers!
...have waylaid the lieutenant.
Speak!
Out of nowhere, a gunshot!
Now I've had enough of this!
Find Lieutenant Alexis right away!
You see, I am he...
The lieutenant.
But what delightful drawers.
Excuse me,
I shall introduce you to my wife!
My dear maiden daughter.
You like my maiden daughter - no?
It won't be so easy
to win my daughter as your wife.
That can't be.
Why did you let him run away?
...and those lovely drawers;
I could have used a pair.
You would have split them though.
You have no idea how cold I am.
The punitive expedition
against the robbers.
Go make some coffee in the meantime.
Children, show some pizzazz!
If you please, maestro.
They're shooting.
Don't get rough.
War is war.
We're not going to allow ourselves
to take a thrashing.
Hi there!
That lass has spirit.
END OF THE SECOND ACT.
THIRD ACT.
A decisive victory.
You went to town on them
like Hector on the steak!
It is to you that we owe
this wonderful victory.
As thanks, you shall receive
my daughter's hand.
I can't possibly ask that of you.
Indeed - you can ask that of me.
Then there's nothing to be done.
The victory celebration.
I've never smelt so good!
Occupied!
Shame on you - in my wardrobe.
Soon we'll be married.
That's what I'm afraid of.
There's nothing to be done -
I'll have to have you arrested.
Out with you, you impertinent being.
Trouble afoot.
Ten legs - five men -
that's about right.
END OF THE THIRD ACT.
FOURTH ACT.
Rischka is dreaming.
Do you hear my heart aflutter?
This is the time of golden love.
The girl has to get married.
You promised her to one of us!
What I've promised, I'll stick to!
You have to get married!
Don't talk so dirty!
Who'd like to marry me?
I would!
Rischka's wedding day.
Do you want to make
my daughter happy?
Always be loyal and honest,
until your chilly grave
Following the young couple's
official wedding yesterday,
today the betrothal
of Lieutenant Alexis
to the daughter of our fortress
commander will be celebrated.
Lieutenant, we must be off
to the wedding celebration.
That would seem to suit you.
I want to go get a little more comfortable!
Why did you give him our child?
He loves you more than me!
I'll cure him of that,
as much as it pains me!
What took you so long?